Guide to the A. P. Watt and Son records, 1861-1971 [bulk 1880-1949]
The New York Public Library. Henry W. and Albert A. Berg Collection of English and American Literature.
- Correspondence, 517474
  - Incoming Correspondence, 517493
    - Orwell, George. TNS to [A. P. Watt and son], 1939 June 21; 517809; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      With carbon of letter from Watt, June 19, 1939
    - Paget, Harold. TLS to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to G. B. Burgin, 1910 Mar. 21; 517810; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Burgin, G. B.))
    - Paget Literary Agency, New York. 2 TL to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to W. B. Yeats' "A prayer for my daughter", 1919 Oct. 29; 517811; in. corr.; 2 p.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Yeats, W. B.))
      Signed C[--?] Paget; In folder with: Monroe, Harriet. ALS to [C--?] Paget. Aug. 17, 1919
    - Paget Literary Agency, New York. 14 TL, 10 telegrams, 1 telegram (copy) to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to use of Sir Arthur Conan Doyle's stories by the National Broadcasting Company, 1930 Aug. 20 - 1932 Mar. 17; 517812; in. corr.; 25 letters in 6 folders (Manuscript box (Doyle, A. C.))
      14 TL signed David Lloyd and A. G. Glidden. With 6 TL (carbon), 7 telegram (copy) replies
    - Paramount Pictures, Inc. 7 TL to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to Rudyard Kipling, 1926 July 22 - 1931 Nov. 17; 517813; in. corr.; 7 letters in 2 folders (Manuscript box (Kipling))
      Signed J[--?] C[--?] Graham and E[--?] Chester. With 3 TL (copy) replies and 4 related memoranda. Accompanied by: Kerly, sons & Karuth. TLS to A. P. Watt and son. Aug. 13, 1926. 1 p. Encloses draft Assignment and Agreement
    - Pemberton, Sir Max. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 May 20; 517814; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - Perth, James Eric Drummond, 16th earl of. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1939 Apr. 27; 517815; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
      With Watt's typed memorandum, dated Aug. 18, 1939. 1 p.
    - Playfair, Giles. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1937 Oct. 12; 517816; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Powell, Anthony. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1939 Feb. 10; 517817; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Press, Gertrude F[--?] L[--?]. TNS to A. P. Watt and son. Written as secretary to H. G. Wells, 1927 Oct. 28; 517818; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Wells))
    - Press, Gertrude F[--?] L[--?]. TNS to A. P. Watt and son. Written as secretary to H. G. Wells, 1927 Nov. 3; 517819; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Wells))
    - Press, Gertrude F[--?] L[--?]. TNS to A. P. Watt and son. Written as secretary to H. G. Wells, 1928 Mar. 15; 517820; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Wells))
    - Press, Gertrude F[--?] L[--?]. TNS to A. P. Watt and son. Written as secretary to H. G. Wells, 1928 Mar. 30; 517821; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Wells))
    - Priestley, John Boynton. TNS to A. P. Watt and son, 1936 June 16; 517822; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Pritchard, Arthur. 2 ALS, 3 ANS to A. P. Watt and son, 1906 Jan. 8 - 1906 Mar. 1; 517823; in. corr.; 5 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box)
      On verso of March 1, 1906 is draft of Watt's reply
    - Quiller-Couch, Sir Arthur Thomas. 2 ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1908 July 26; 1908 Dec. 11; 517824; in. corr.; 1 p. each (Manuscript box)
    - Redesdale, Algernon Bertram Freeman-Mitford, baron. ANS to A. P. Watt and son, 1915 Nov. 4; 517825; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Renaissance Film Co. 4 TL to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to W. B. Maxwell's The guarded flame, 1916 Jan. 27 - 1916 May 30; 517826; in. corr.; 2 p.; 1 p.; 1 p.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Maxwell, W. B.))
    - Reynolds, Gertrude M. (Robins). ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 May 23; 517827; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Rhodes, Geoffrey. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1937 Sept. 4; 517828; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      Encloses: Burgin, George Brown. ALS to A. P. Watt and son. Sept. 2, 1937. 1 p.; with Watt's TL (carbon) reply
    - Rhodes, Kathlyn. 3 TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1913 Sept. 1 - 1913 Sept. 17; 517829; in. corr.; 1 p. each (Manuscript box)
    - Richards, Grant, publisher, London. TLS to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to George Randolph Chester, 1914 June 5; 517830; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Chester, G. R.))
    - Richards, Grant, publisher, London. TLS to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to Montague Marsden Glass, 1918 Aug. 22; 517831; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Glass, M. M.))
    - Roberts, Morley. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 May 18; 517832; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Ruck, Berta. AN to [A. P. Watt and son], 517833; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      Accompanied by 2 watercolor drawings of flowers, one dated Sept. 1916
    - Sabatini, Rafael. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1910 Dec. 21; 517834; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Saer, Ethel. 3 ALS to A. P. Watt and son. Two letters dated July 29, 1935 and relate to Elizabeth Kenny, 1935 July 29; [n.d; 517835; in. corr.; 1 p.; 2 leaves; 2 leaves (Manuscript box)
    - Scott-Moncrieff, William Dundas. 5 ALS, 2 ANS to A. P. Watt and son, 1881 Jan. 29 - 1881 Mar. 22; 517836; in. corr.; 7 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box)
      With "Extract from the minutes of the meeting held at 9 Barton Street, Westminster, on the 12th Feb. 1881," holograph, 2 p.
    - Sharp, Margery. Postcard to A. P. Watt and son. Date from postmark, 1932 Sept. 1; 517837; in. corr.; 1 card (Manuscript box)
    - Silberrad, Una Lucy. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1904 Mar. 24; 517838; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
      Published in Letters to A. P. Watt and his sons, 1883-1924. London, 1924, p. 191
    - Simpson, Bertram Lenox. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1909 July 18; 517839; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Smith, Ernest Bramah. 2 TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1933 Jan. 18 - 1935 May 23; 517840; in. corr.; 1 p. each (Manuscript box)
    - Smith, Robert Pearsall. 2 ALS to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to George MacDonald's The elect lady, 1887 Dec. 8; 517841; in. corr.; 1 p.; 2 p (Manuscript box (MacDonald, G.))
      Letter beginning "I enc. The Xn Union acceptance" encloses: Mabie, Hamilton Wright. Letter (copy) to Robert Pearsall Smith. Dec. 6, 1887. 2 p.
    - Southgate, Lucienne. ANS, 9 TLS, 4 TNS to A. P. Watt and son. Written as secretary to H. G. Wells, 1928 Oct. 20 - 1931 Aug. 20; 517842; in. corr.; 14 letters in 3 folders (Manuscript box (Wells))
      With carbons of 6 letters from Watt to Miss Southgate, Feb. 26, 1930-Sept. 7, 1931. Enclosed in Mar. 21, 1931: Wells, H.G. 2 TL (copies) to Newman Flower [of Cassell * Co., Ltd., London] Mar. 14, 1931. 1 p.; Mar. 19, 1931. 2 p.
    - [Southwold, Stephen]. 2 AL to A. P. Watt and son, 1935 Oct. 15; 1935 Oct. 27; 517843; in. corr.; 1 p. each (Manuscript box)
      Signed Neil Bell [pseud.]
    - Spence, Edward Fordham. 3 ALS, 4 ANS to A. P. Watt and son, 1886 July 13 - 1886 Sept. 3; 517844; in. corr.; 7 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box)
    - Sprigge, Sir Samuel Squire. ANS to A. P. Watt and son, 1901 Nov. 15; 517845; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Besant, W.))
      Receipt on conjugate leaf for his work as editor of Sir Walter Besant's Autobiography
    - Stannard, Arthur. 6 ALS, 1 telegram to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to Henrietta Eliza Vaughn Stannard, 1887 May 25 - 1887 June 25; 517846; in. corr.; 7 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box)
    - Stannard, Henrietta Eliza Vaughan. ALS to [A. P. Watt and son], 1887 June 5; 517847; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - Strong, Leonard Alfred George. 3 ALS, 2 TLS, 1 TNS to A. P. Watt and son, 1931 Aug. 21 - 1932 Apr. 4; 517848; in. corr.; 6 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box)
    - Sutcliffe, Halliwell. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1904 Mar. 26; 517849; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - Swinton, Sir Ernest Dunlop. ANS to A. P. Watt and son, 1940 Jan. 29; 517850; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Terry, Ellen. ALS, LS to A. P. Watt and son, 1908 Jan. 25; 1908 Oct. 18; 517851; in. corr.; 1 p.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - Thring, George Herbert. ALS to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to Marguerite O'Key Labori, 1936 Jan. 6; 517852; in. corr.; 3 p (Manuscript box)
      With related typed memorandum by Watt, Jan. 9, 1936. 1 p.
    - Thurston, Ernest Temple. TNS to A. P. Watt and son, 1915 Nov. 17; 517853; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      Encloses: Nash's Magazine. TL, signed Perriton maxwell, to Ernest Temple Thurston. July 21, 1914. 1 p.
    - Tillotson & Son, Ltd. Note to [A. P. Watt and son]. Relates to Charles Gibbon, 1884 Nov. 17; 517854; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Gibbon, C.))
    - Tillotson & Son., Ltd. 3 letters, 1 TL to A. P. Watt and son. One letter undated. Relate to Henrietta Eliza Vaughan Stannard, 1887 June 14 - 1887 June 24; 517855; in. corr.; 1 p. each (Manuscript box (Stannard))
      Signed William Frank Tillotson
    - Tillotson & Son, Ltd. 4 TLS, 1 LS, postcard and telegram to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to Sir Henry Rider Haggard and Wilkie Collins, 1884 Nov. 27 - 1887 May 24; 517856; in. corr.; 7 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box (Haggard))
    - Untermeyer, Louis. 4 TL (carbons) to A. P. Watt and son as literary agent for David Garnett, 517857; in. corr.; 1 p. each (Manuscript box (Garnett))
      Also: 6 TLS of related correspondence
    - Vaughan, Charles John. ALS to [A. P. Watt and son?], 1886 Sept. 13; 517858; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
    - Villiers, Alan John. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1937 Aug. 25; 517859; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Vowles, Hugh Pembroke. 3 TLS to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to writer's collaboration with H. G. Wells on The work, wealth and happiness of mankind, 1929 Mar. 25 - 1929 Sept. 24; 517860; in. corr.; 1 p. each (Manuscript box (Wells))
    - Vyver, Bertha. 3 ALS, 3 ANS to A. P. Watt and son. Writer was secretary to Marie Corelli, 1915 Dec. 14 - 1938 Dec. 29; 517861; in. corr.; 6 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box (Corelli))
    - Walker, Ethel. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1899 July 13; 517862; in. corr.; 5 p (Manuscript box)
    - Walker-Smith, Sir Derek. TNS to A. P. Watt and son, 1936 July 28; 517863; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Wall, Caroline Heron. ALS to [A. P. Watt and son], 1886 Sept. 10; 517864; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
      With related ALS from Arthur Blackett to Watt, July 16, 1886. 2 p.
    - Wallace, Edgar. Postcard to A. P. Watt and son, 1914 Feb. 18; 517865; in. corr.; 1 card (Manuscript box)
    - Walston, Sir Charles. TLS, TNS to A. P. Watt and son, 1925 Aug. 7; 1926 mar. 27; 517866; in. corr.; 1 p. each (Manuscript box)
    - Watson, Rev. John W. Letter and ANS to A. P. Watt and son, 1899 July 14; 1899 July 20; 517867; in. corr.; 1 p. each (Manuscript box)
      Letter signed for Watson
    - Watson, Margaret. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1899 July 20; 517868; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - Wavell, Archibald Percival Wavell, 1st earl. ALS, ANS to [A. P. Watt and son], 1937 Aug. 7; 1937 Feb. 5; 517869; in. corr.; 1 p.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
      With carbons of three letters from Watt and one memorandum, Aug. 5, 1936 - Feb. 9, 1937
    - Wells, Amy Catherine (Robbins). 7 ALS (1 incomplete), 2 ANS, 2 TLS to A. P. Watt and son. Writer is wife of H. G. Wells, 1926 Oct. 12 - [1927] Mar. 2; 517870; in. corr.; 11 letters in 3 folders (Manuscript box (Wells))
      With carbons of 10 letters from Watt to Catherine Wells
    - Wells, George Philip. Telegram to A. P. Watt and son. Writer is the son of H. G. Wells, 1929 Jan. 19; 517871; in. corr.; 1 letter (Manuscript box (Wells))
      With carbons of 3 letters from Watt to G. P. Wells
    - Wells, Herbert George. 32 ALS, 1 TLS, 5 TLS to A. P. Watt and son, 1917 Jan.] - 1937 Jan. 22; 517872; in. corr.; 38 letters in 8 folders (Manuscript box)
    - Wells, Marjorie (Craig). 9 TLS, 4 TNS to A. P. Watt and son. Written as secretary to H. G. Wells, 1926 Nov. 29 - 1931 Oct. 16; 517873; in. corr.; 13 letters in 3 folders (Manuscript box (Wells))
      With carbons of 12 letters from Watt to Marjorie Wells
    - White, F. V., and Co., firm, publishers, London. 4 letters to A. P. Watt and son. Two letters dated July 30, 1886. Relate to E. F. Spence, 1886 July 30 - 1886 Aug. 17; 517874; in. corr.; 1 p.; 2 leaves; 2 p.; 2 leaves (Manuscript box (Spence, E. F.))
    - White, Fred Merrick. ALS, ANS to A. P. Watt and son, 1899 July 12; 1899 July 19; 517875; in. corr.; 1 p.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - White, Richard C. ALS to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to his dramatization of Sir H. R. Haggard's She in collaboration with J. O. Barrows, 1887 Sept. 2; 517876; in. corr.; 2 leaves (Manuscript box (Haggard))
    - Wild, Roland. TLS to A. P. Watt and son, n.y.] Dec. 29; 517877; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Williamson, Emma Sara. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, n.y. Mar. 18; 517878; in. corr.; 3 p (Manuscript box)
    - Wilson, Andrew. 1 ALS, 2 ANS, 3 telegrams (1 mutilated) to A. P. Watt and son. Relate to advertisements in Health, of which Watt was publisher and Wilson editor, 1888 Feb. 22 - [1899] July 20; 517879; in. corr.; 6 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box)
      Letter of Feb. 22, 1888, encloses his: ALS to C[--?] B[--?] Harness. Feb. 22, 1888. 3 p.
    - Wolfe, Humbert. TL (carbon) to A. P. Watt and son, 1916 Feb. 21; 517880; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      Signed U. Wolff. On verso is holograph line from his "The Drift of the lute" from London sonnets
    - Woods, Mary. ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1906 Apr. 5; 517881; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - Wright, H. 2 ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 517882; in. corr.; 3 p. each (Manuscript box)
    - Wyatt, Stanley Porter (?) ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1911 Nov. 27; 517883; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - Yeats, William Butler. 6 ALS, 2 TLS, 2 LS to A. P. Watt and son. Letter of April 27, 1924 mentions Thomas Hardy, 1918] Dec. 2 - 1924 Apr. 27; 517884; in. corr.; 10 letters in 2 folders (Manuscript box)
    - Yeats-Brown, Francis Charles Claypon. TNS to A. P. Watt and son, 1934 Apr. 25; 517885; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Yorkshire Cine Co., Ltd., London. TL to A. P. Watt and son. Relates to H. A. Vachell's The hill, 1916 Apr. 27; 517886; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Vachell))
      Signed J. G. R. Hughes
    - Young, Emily Hilda. 5 ALS to A. P. Watt and son, 1931 Jan. 17 - 1931 June 3; 517887; in. corr.; 5 letters in 1 folder (Manuscript box)
      Signed Emily H. Daniell; Accompanied by: Henderson, R. G. ANS to [A. P. Watt and son], April 1, 1931. 1 p.
  - Incoming Correspondence related to A. P. Watt and Son, 517888
    - Champion de Crespigny, Rose (Key). ALS to [Alexander Strahan] Watt. Letter of condolence on death of Mrs. Watt, 1908] Dec. 16; 517889; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
    - Crockett, Samuel Rutherford. ALS to [Alexander Strahan] Watt. Letter of condolence on death of Mrs. Watt, 1909] Jan. 17; 517890; in. corr.; 3 p (Manuscript box)
    - Harvey, George. ALS to Alexander Strahan Watt. Letter of condolence on death of Mrs. Watt, 1908 Dec. 6; 517891; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
    - Hinkson, Katherine (Tynan). ALS to Alexander Strahan Watt. Letter of condolence on death of Mrs. Watt, 1908 Dec. 10; 517892; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Le Feuvre, Amy. ALS to Alexander Strahan Watt. Letter of condolence on death of Mrs. Watt, 1908 Dec. 20; 517893; in. corr.; 3 p (Manuscript box)
    - Leighton, Marie (Connor). ALS to Alexander Strahan Watt. Letter of condolence on death of Mrs. Watt, 1908 Dec. 8; 517894; in. corr.; 2 leaves (Manuscript box)
    - Moore, Frank Frankfort. ALS to [Alexander Strahan] Watt. Letter of condolence on death of Mrs. Watt, 1908 Dec. 8; 517895; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - Nash, J. [--?] Eveleigh. ANS to ALS to [Alexander Strahan] Watt. Letter of condolence on death of Mrs. Watt, 1908 Dec. 8; 517896; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Smith, Annie S[--?] (Swan). AL to Alexander Strahan Watt. Letter of condolence on death of Mrs. Watt, 1908] Dec. 12; 517897; in. corr.; 3 p (Manuscript box)
      Signed Annie Burnett Smith
    - Vachell, Horace Annesley. ALS to Alexander Strahan Watt. Letter of condolence on death of Mrs. Watt, 1908] Dec. 15; 517898; in. corr.; 1 leaf (Manuscript box)
    - Wallace, William. ALS to Alexander Strahan Watt. Letter of condolence on death of Mrs. Watt, 1908; 517899; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Weyman, Stanley John. ALS to Alexander Strahan Watt. Letter of condolence on death of Mrs. Watt, 1908 Dec. 8; 517900; in. corr.; 2 p (Manuscript box)
    - Seldes, Gilbert Vivian. TL (carbon) to H. Watt. Relates to W. B. Yeats, 1922 July 25; 517901; related corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
      With: Seldes, Gilbert Vivian. 9 TLS, 1 telegram, 1 postcard to James Sibley Watson, Jr. April 3, 1922-[June 1, 1970] 2 folders. Came with J. S. Watson's papers
    - MacLehose, Hamish A.(?). ALS to William Watt, 1931 Sept. 8; 517902; in. corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box (Watt, A. P.))
    - M[--?], F[--?] F[--?]. Postcard to W[--?] P[--?] Watt, 1912] Dec. 27; 517903; in. corr.; 1 card (Manuscript box (Watt, A. P.))
  - Other Related Correspondence, 517904
    - Doyle, Sir Arthur Conan. ALS to Meyrick Jones. Mentions A. P. Watt & Son, n.y. Feb. 5; 517905; related corr.; 1 p (Manuscript box)
    - Haggard, Sir Henry Rider. 3 AL (drafts), telegram (holograph copy) to Richard C. White. Drafted for A. P. Watt & son. First letter addressed jointly to White and James O. Barrows, 1887; 517906; related corr.; 1 leaf; 1 leaf; 1 p.; 2 leaves (Manuscript box)